# Mark L. Lintern

### **Computer Engineer**

markllintern@gmail.com 
419 - 571 - 9960 
Indianapolis, IN, USA 
linkedin.com/in/mlintern in
github.com/mlintern git
github.com/nretnilkram git

Motivated Computer Engineer with 10+ years of SaaS experience and proven full stack skills from **HTML** to **DevOps**. Seeking a position that will allow me to push my abilities to the next level. I have developed many web applications in **Ruby** which enhanced and enabled faster testing processes. I am excited to be a valued, key contributor on a software engineering team.

#### **SKILLS**

Advanced: Ruby MySQL HTML5 CSS JavaScript JQuery Bash Git Jenkins Browserstack

Intermediate: PostgreSQL MongoDB Apache nginx Docker PHP VirtualBox Vagrant OracleDB C++ Python

Java TeamCity Backbone Kubernetes Code Linters Code Documetation Unit Testing

Basic: React Exchange Bomgar Kaseya True Crypt Mozy Online Backup Exec Mathematica

OS: Windows OS MAC OS X Linux OS Windows Server

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Oracle Corporation / Compendium (Aquired January 2014)

September 2010 - March 2019

### Senior Quality Assurance Engineer

February 2017 - March 2019

Indianapolis, IN, USA

- o Continuation of previous Quality Assurance Engineering role with following additional responsibilities.
- Engineered and Implemented code changes to assist with development team for bugs and design updates.
- Maintained Saltstack configuration scripts for development, test, qa, and production environments. As well as Bash scripts for bootstrapping developers host machines.
- Served as Compendium's project manager. Tracked and reported progress throughout the agile process to assure deadlines were met.
- Lead Quality Assurance Engineer for the Oracle Marketing Cloud Framework application (AMS) within the Oracle Cloud.
- Created and maintained an automation testing suite for the OMC Framework application written in Java and Selenium Webdriver driven by JUnit, which executed as a TeamCity build on a regular schedule.
- Performed deployments of **Docker** containers to our OMC Framework QA environtment through a **Kubernetes** management software, Rancher.

### **Quality Assurance Engineer**

January 2014 - February 2017

Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Reviewed and tested new features and bug fix merge requests using a locally maintained development environment and test environment.
- Developed and maintained **Ruby** web application with functionalities that include network cloning, network population, and content scrambler for the Compendium product.
- Created and maintained an automation testing suite for the Compendium application written in Ruby and Selenium Webdriver driven by MiniTest, which executed as a Jenkins job on a regular schedule.
- Facilitated migration of DNS, email, and website during the Compendium acquisition by Oracle.

### **Implementation Specialist**

July 2012 - January 2014

Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Implementated customer designs from Photoshop into **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, and **JQuery** in our template management tool.
- Wrote and execute content import and export scripts in PHP and Ruby using the Compendium Rest API.
- Planned and executed the office move, which included designing and setup of wiring tower.
- Split time between company integrations, implementation and maintenance of **HTML** designs, and Product Support.
- Migrated customer support request system from Salesforce to a Zendesk Salesforce integration.
- Resolved customer support requests via phone and email and tracked them with Zendesk.
- Maintained internal systems, new user setups, user laptop configuration and company-wide network configuration.

### **Information Technologies Administrator**

September 2010 - July 2012 Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Configured and maintained internal Active Directory, DHCP, and DNS Services.
- Created and executed a moving plan for office equipment, phone system and network.
- Planned and executed successful email migration from Microsoft Exchange internal server to Google Apps.
- Maintained Bacula backup system then migrated it to Windows Backup once everyone switched to MAC.
- Built and maintained internal web servers build on Cent OS and Apache.
- Migrated DNS and DHCP from Linux BIND and DHCP to Windows Server 2008 Native Applications.
- Upgraded and maintained Samba Network Storage Server with OpenLDAP and Active Directory integration.

**Qbase Inc.** May 2008 - September 2010

### Support Desk Analyst II

November 2009 - September 2010

Beavercreek, OH, USA

- o Performed routine outbound maintenance and repairs for hardware and software when necessary.
- Implemented and maintained security protocols company wide through group policy and third party software.
- Supported Altigen IP phone systems for managed companies as well as own internal phone network.
- Created and maintained backup solutions, both on-line as well as physical drives, onsite and remotely.
- Trained new employees how to deal with common issues and software tools used within the company.
- Worked directly with the director of IT solutions.

#### Support Desk Analyst I

May 2008 - November 2009

Beavercreek, OH, USA

- Performed remote, phone and email support using verbal instruction and remote control software.
- Supported the various software, hardware and network issues of more than 300 companies.
- Managed servers, workstations, routers and switches for approximately 30 companies subscribing to the managed services opportunities provided by the support staff with a third party software.
- Performed virus control measures for both pre infection prevention as well as post infection removal.
- Utilized the connectwise support application to track user requests from trouble ticket generation to resolution.
- Hand built servers and workstations as well as installed hardware and software as requested by client.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

## O Ruby Gems

- o compendium-api: utilizes compendium api with easy function calls for **Ruby** scripting. gh/mlintern/compendium-api
- o nretnil-password: easy password, passphrase and uuid generation. gh/nretnilkram/nretnil-password
- nretnil-fake-data: great for creating fake data such as names and dates. gh/nretnilkram/nretnil-fake-data
- o nretnil-utilites: a set of utilies which extends Array, Hash, String and Integer classes. gh/nretnilkram/nretnil-utilities
- o nretnil-translate: a gem which translates text into Pig Latin or a simple scramble. gh/nretnilkram/nretnil-translate

## O Personal Websites / Apps for pleasure and assistance in development

- o nretnil.com, practical site of my commonly used online tools built primarily with **JavaScript** and **PHP**.
- marklintern.com, personal site.
- o app.nretnil.com, **Ruby** Padrino App that handles account management, sessions, and authentication.
- lintern.us, fun site with family photos displayed as if they are polarids on a cork board.
- sandybox.nretnil.com, HTML and JavaScript sandbox environment utilizing the JavaScript Ace Editor.
- o dice.nretnil.com, randomized results for numbers, letters, 6-sided dice values, or custom characters.

## JavaScript / CSS Projects

• Fontstrap: CSS/JavaScript project combining Bootstrap and Fontawesome along with custom features and scripts. https://nretnilkram.github.io/fontstrap

#### **EDUCATION**

## Wittenberg University

August 2004 - May 2008

Springfield, OH, USA

- Bachelor of Science Computer ScienceBachelor of Arts Mathematics